（忙碌海狸五金店）
欢迎来到本店
Welcome to the store.
你是忙碌的海狸吗？
Are you a Busy Beaver?
不，我不是忙碌的海狸
No, I am not a Busy Beaver.
（绳）
你是海狸会员吗？
Are you a Frequent Beaver?
加入奖赏计划尽享折扣
Join our rewards club for savings.
你可咬紧我们的超抵优惠
You can get your teeth
别忘了
Don't forget:
若需要协助，请找海狸帮忙
If you need help, ask a Beaver.
Oh. Oh.
嘿，我能帮你吗，先生？
Hey. Oh.
你认为我不懂得割绳？
Do you think
不，只是通常由我们代劳
No, it's just we usually do that for ya.
你认为我会割伤自己？
流到一地血，然后告你？
不是
No.
那我不需要你帮忙
Then I don't need your help.
祝你有愉快的一天
Have an excellent day.
我是只忙碌的海狸
I'm a Busy Beaver.
蠢材
Idiot.
你想买的今天都找到了吗？
Did you, um, find everything
是
Yes.
很好
Good.
我们看看
Let's see here.
总共 3.47 元
Uh, your total is 3.47.
你收了我六尺绳的价钱
You charged me for 6 feet of rope.
是的，99 分一码
Oh, yes, it's 99¢ a yard.
我没买两码，只买了五尺
I didn't get 2 yards. I got 5 feet.
是，但我们不以尺收费，用码来算
Yeah, we don't charge by the foot.
99 分一码即 33 分一尺
乘以 5，是 1.65 元
你收了我 1.98 元
You charged me $1.98.
你算术真好
You're good at math. Um...
是的，我知道
但这样入不到机，如果照你所讲
什么垃圾电脑连简单算术也做不到？
What the hell kind of computer
- 叫你经理出来
- 他去了吃午餐
午餐，现在所有人都只关心午餐
Lunch. All anyone cares about
- 有其他负责人吗？
- 副经理之类？
- 是，我想找副经理
- 好
嘿，泰勒？
Hey, Taylor?
泰勒？来前面收银处
Taylor? To the front register.
怎么了？
What's up?
嘿，泰勒
Hey, Taylor.
这就是副经理？她几岁？
This is the assistant manager?
你不是该去上体育课？
Shouldn't you be in gym class?
对不起，什么？
Sorry, what?
拿去，我有些零钱
Here. I got some change.
我帮你付额外那 33 分
Let me cover that extra 33¢ for you.
先生，我不想要你那 33 分
这也不是 33 分的问题
问题是我买了五尺绳，因为我只要五尺
This is about the fact that I got 5 feet
我不该付六尺的钱
因为我不想要六尺绳
你想要多一尺绳？
Did you want another foot of rope?
《隐闭中年》
别再来派
Not again.
Hm.
这能有多难？
How hard can this be?
（非住户绝不能丢任何东西进垃圾桶！）
单车要放这边
That bike goes over here.
嘿！你搞什么？
Hey! What the hell?
那是我的
That's mine.
- 该放在单车架上
- 我只行开了半分钟
下次，我会把它锁在失物认领处
Next time, I'll lock it up
暴躁阿伯
Grumpy old bastard.
老天
Jeez.
（泊车证 桦木庄居民）
没挂在倒后镜
Not on the mirror.
嘿，奥图！
-Hey, Otto!
好了
Okay.
嘿！
Hey!
（美利健四德地产）
别再让那老鼠狗在我的前廊痾尿
Don't you dare let that little rat dog
- 我知道是你
- 别理他，王子
他是个刻薄老头
根本不知道是谁做的
不是它就是你
Well, it was one of you.
还有叫你那废柴男友
别在公众地方扭下盘
像个14岁的罗马尼亚体操选手，离谱
Looks like a 14-year-old Romanian gymnast,
走，走开
Go on. Get outta here.
走啊
Go.
（工程部）
来了，大人物来了
There he is, the big man himself.
搞什么？
What's all this?
这是退休蛋糕，随你怎么称呼
It's, well, retirement cake, I guess.
（贺奥图荣休
好好享受）
“好好享受”
"Have fun."
享受什么？
Doing what?
祝你余生尽情享乐，我们想…
Have fun with the rest of your life.
庆祝？
Celebrate?
是啊！不…
Yes! Well, no.
只是好好欢送你
Give you a nice send-off.
“好好”
"Nice."
来嘛，奥图
Come on, Otto.
是你决定要离职的
You're the one who decided to leave.
而且你拿到了很不错的“肥鸡餐”
And you did get a nice severance package.
你把我调出运营部
You took me off Operations.
减我工时
You cut back on my hours.
你让我训练出来的泰利做我上司
You made Terry,
泰利若没手机在旁
连今年是边年都搞不清
所以是的，我接受了肥鸡餐
So, yes, I took the severance package.
我很遗憾你这样想
I'm sorry you see it that way.
合并后，我们全体都要作调整
We all had to adjust after the merger.
但你多年来
都是本公司的重要资产，所以…
真的，你可靠得要命
You have. Reliable as hell.
我们会想念你那些日程表
We're gonna miss
敬奥图！
To Otto!
- 敬奥图！
- 敬奥图
好了，奥图
要一件你的脸？
谁饿了？
-Who's hungry?
（非直通街道）
（只限有许可证车辆 及 不准泊车）
看啊…
Look at this.
不，不行
No, no.
嘿！嘿，等等！
Hey, hey, wait!
不行！你没许可证不能用这条路
No, no, no. Hey, you cannot use
我不是泊车，只是送包裹
I'm not parking.
标志上没写什么包裹，对吧？
The sign doesn't say
上面写 “许可证”，而你没有
It says "permits" and you don't have one.
这不是直通街道
This is not a through street.
祝你今天愉快，先生
Have a nice day, sir.
每次你开车进来
Every time you come in here
就代表有住户不能在家门前泊车！
that means one of the residents
开白色货车那些人不会这样
The other guys don't do this.
次次都是你们这些啡色人
How come it's always you brown guys?
我不是指肤色！
And I don't mean that racially!
你好
Hello.
嗨，对不起，你听到吗？
Oh, hi. Sorry, can you hear me?
听到
Yes.
我是苏珊
It's Susan.
哪个苏珊？
Susan who?
关于你的健康保险，我有个好消息
I have great news
不，不…机械人！机械人！
Oh, no, no, no. Robot, robot, robot!
我要找谁才可中止电话服务？
Well, who do I have to talk to
要找客户服务
That's Account Services.
能帮我转驳吗？还是要揿号码？
Can you transfer me
我已经听了七分钟音乐
Well, I have been listening
很抱歉，安达臣先生
I do apologise, Mr Anderson.
我想中止这寓所的供电
I would like the electricity shut off
- 你要搬屋？
- 不，我要取消帐户
A-N-D-E-R-S-O-N
A-N-D-E-R-S-O-N.
为何这六天不能退钱？
And why can't you refund me
O-T-T-O
O-T-T-O.
噢，是规矩
Oh, it's policy.
那我的规矩是
若我要付六天的煤气费
那我就要用那六天的煤气
then I will use six days of gas.
然后就解决了
Then we are done here.
蠢材
Idiots.
好了
Okay.
继续，继续
停！继续
好了，停
Okay. Yeah. Stop.
退后，你在盲点上
小心，运用原力
好极…
不，你上了行人路
好了
Okay.
退后…退后…
Back, back, back.
退开
Go away.
停！
-Stop. Stop.
激气
Ah, shit.
他在搞什么？
What the hell is he doing?
对！就是！
我就是那样骂他的
嘿，你不能在这乱开车
-Hey, you can't just drive here.
我没在开车
我在开车吗？没有
你没许可证，不能随便开车进来
You can't just bring a car
不，我们有泊车证
在这里，看？
你放在口袋把鬼？
What the hell's it doing in your pocket?!
嗯…因为我是驾驶者
Well, I'm the driver.
我们租住了这里，是啊
We're renting here. Yeah.
住 206 号
In 206.
那不代表你可把拖车泊到前门
That doesn't mean you can back
不，我没有…我是想平行泊车
No, I wasn't. I was, uh, parallel parking.
同边度平行？
Parallel to what?
是啊，泊得不太好，对吧？
Yeah, that, uh, didn't go so well, huh?
我再试试
I'll just give it another try.
噢，天啊
-Oh, my God.
好了
Okay.
Mm...
好，很好！
Good. Good!
继续倒后，继续倒后
Keep backing away. Keep backing away.
再倒后些
Now go away more.
好了，我搞得掂
Okay, I got this.
- 另一边，先倒另一边
- 慢慢
对了
-Easy.
- 慢慢，慢慢
- 很好
不…搞什么？不！
No. No, no. What? No!
不要！停！停车！
-No, no, no! Stop! Stop, stop, stop! Stop!
停车！停车！你落车
-Stop! Stop. Get outta the car.
- 落车
- 很抱歉
你咁大个人
How you could make it
竟然不懂倒泊拖车
without knowing how to back up a trailer.
老天，跛了前脚
兼有白内障的狗都泊得比你好
自动波，果然
车匙给我
噢，在杯架上
Oh, they're in the cupholder.
这车是按掣起动的
It's a push-button start.
不，我知道
No, I knew that.
那是什么鬼？
What the hell is that?
是雷达
Uh, that's the radar.
拖车离车边太近
The trailer's too close
所以不断哔，但它…
That's why it's still beeping, but--
好吧
Okay.
哈罗
Hello.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
- 奥图
- 奥图？
奥图，O-T-T-O
Otto. O-T-T-O.
我叫艾比，O-T-T-O
I'm Abbie, O-T-T-O.
我叫露娜
And I'm Luna.
很高兴认识你们
Nice to meet you.
他开得很好
Oh, that was good, huh?
他一次就泊好？
He just did it in one shot, huh?
- 完美！
- 谢谢，先生
任何认为倒车要用雷达的人
Anyone who thinks
都应被禁止开车
shouldn't be allowed to drive one.
更应被禁用无线电
They shouldn't be allowed
我也这样认为
That's what I said.
许可证要挂上倒后镜
不是放口袋里！
- 知道了
- 收到
- 拜拜！多谢！
- 谢谢，先生，你真好人
蠢材
Idiot.
你们都准备好？
You guys all ready?
好了
Okay.
行了
All right.
带齐你们的东西，好吗？
Bring your stuff, okay?
来吧，宝贝们
Come on, sweeties.
孩子们，带齐物品
Chiquitita, take your stuff.
（《大师与玛格丽特》）
书架还有几多位？
How much more shelf space is left?
三格
Three shelves.
- 你还有几箱书？
- 七、八箱
“那我帮你造多个书架”
"Then I'll build you another bookcase."
那我帮你造多个书架
Then I'll build you another bookcase.
- 嗨
- 嘿
嗨，傲图
Hi. Otto.
对吗？是吗？
Right? Yes?
奥图
Otto.
我就是那样说，不是吗？我说了…
Yeah, that's what I said.
你说了什么不重要
奥图，O-T-T-O
- 奥图
-Ah! Otto.
奥图…所以前后倒转都是一样
Otto. Okay, so it's the same forward
- 奥图
- 是奥图，玛丽
很少会听到这名字
It's just you don't hear
我常常听到啊
I do.
好吧，若打扰了你
我们稍后再来
你们想怎样？
What is it you want?
我带了些食物给你
I brought you some food.
为什么？
Why?
因为你看起来很饿
Because you looked hungry.
所以我们很合衬
That's why we go so well together.
她爱做菜，而我什么都爱吃
She loves to cook,
总之，我们只是…
Anyway, we just, uh...
我们只想好好介绍自己
We wanted
因为我们会成为邻居，所以…
because we're gonna be neighbours
- 所以…
- 好
- 好吧
- 拜拜
我叫玛莉素
My name is Marisol.
而我叫汤美
And I'm Tommy.
奥图
Otto.
你总是这么不友善？
Are you always this unfriendly?
我没有不友善
I'm not unfriendly.
- 我觉得你有点不友善
- 我没有
- 有一点
没有？好吧，你没有
No? Okay, you're not.
不，没有，你没有不友善
No, no, no, no. You're not unfriendly.
你说的每个字
都像个温暖的拥抱
真的
It really is.
好好享用
Enjoy it.
这是什么？
What is it?
小心漏汁，拜托
Be careful with the salsa, please.
是浓酱鸡
It's, um, pollo con mole.
很好吃的
It's really good.
是墨西哥菜
It's a Mexican dish.
我是墨西哥人
I'm Mexican.
我在萨尔瓦多出世，我爸是那里人
I was born in El Salvador
但我妈是墨西哥人
所以我们先去了墨西哥，然后…
- 你呢？
- 我是电脑技术顾问
噢，我来自安那翰
Oh, I'm from Anaheim.
噢，来自安那翰
Oh, from Anaheim.
安那翰，是的
Anaheim, yeah.
是啊，厄尔巴索
Yeah. El Paso.
好吧，我有些事要做
Okay, well, I have some things
不好意思，奥图先生
Excuse me, Mr Otto.
你有星型扳手可以借我吗？
You wouldn't have an Alvin wrench
你指六角扳手
You mean an Allen wrench.
不，星型扳手
No, an Alvin wrench.
- 那叫六角扳手
- 六角扳手
是“六角”扳手，对吧？
六角扳手
是“星形”
It's Alvin.
整个早上都说星形扳手
All morning, "Alvin wrench, Alvin wrench."
老婆，是叫星形扳手，信我
Honey, it's Alvin, trust me.
我认识的人都叫它星形扳手
Everybody else I know
- 你认识的人都讲错，唔好意思
- 是吗？要上 Google 查吗？
天啊
My God.
查 Google 啊
Google it! Google it!
查维基…查维基
Google it. Wikipediale. Wikipediale.
你的手机给我
Give me your phone.
别用我的，你用你的手机
No, my phone. You use your phone.
你知要什么尺寸吗？
Do you know what size you need?
就…一般尺寸
Ah, just the usual size.
全套拿去
Take the set.
- 谢谢
-Thank you.
我们走了，因为你有事要做，所以…
We go because you have things to do, so...
你想要什么？
What do you want, huh?
Mmm.
Mmm!
Hm.
Mmm.
很美吧，儿子？
Isn't she beautiful, son?
那就是雪佛兰引擎
That's a Chevy engine for you.
可靠
Dependable.
这世上你能依靠的不多
Not enough you can depend on
爸，这是奥图
Dad, this is Otto.
已经够了，亲爱的
That's enough now, darling.
（鲜花 8 元两束）
Huh.
8 元两束？
Two for $8?
或者我该直接用车撞死自己
那一定成功
我带了你喜欢的花来
Found some of the flowers you like.
粉红色的
Pink.
有折
There was a deal on 'em.
做特价，8 元两束
On sale. Two for 8 bucks.
我很抱歉没早一点带花来看你
I'm sorry I didn't get 'em here earlier.
有事耽搁了
Got distracted.
因为一家新邻居
By some new neighbours.
个老公蠢蠢钝钝
Nitwit husband.
连六角扳手都讲错
Didn't even know an Allen wrench
那间屋当然是租的
Renters, of course.
对任何事都没担当
No commitment to anything.
（桑雅）
我知道，他们可能还未买得起
I know, I know.
但是，若那些房地产混蛋
But what will they do
决定拆他们的房子
decide to tear down their house
用来建更多廉价单调的公寓怎么办？
and put up more
一定会发生的，我保证
It's gonna happen. I promise you.
他们已经绕过闸门开车
They're already driving around the gates,
直接驶上草地
driving right across the grass.
美利健四德
Dye & Merika.
哪个蠢材认为这名字适合地产公司？
What idiot thought that was a good name
听落似“美利坚死得”
Sounds like "dying America."
事实上也是
It is, of course.
现在连稳阵的螺丝钩都买不到了
Can't even buy
以尺数买绳也不行
Or rope by the foot.
你不在家，诸事不顺
Nothing works when you're not home.
下一位
Next.
我怀疑你有肥厚型心肌病
I suspect you have
那是遗传性的增大…
which is a genetic enlargement of the--
我知道
I know.
我父亲也有
My father had it.
好吧，你应该可以活很久的…
Well, you'll likely be around
但恐怕你的军途到此为止
but I'm afraid
下一位
Next.
一张回匹兹堡的车票
One return ticket to Pittsburgh, please.
1.10 元
That'll be 1.10.
谢谢
Thank you.
借过
Coming through.
嘿，你的书掉了！
Hey, you dropped your book!
小姐，你的书掉了！嘿！
Miss, you dropped your book! Hey!
那是我的吗？
Is that mine?
什么？
What?
是的，我见到你掉了，所以我…
-Yes. I saw you dropped it, so I...
（《大师与玛格丽特》）
很感谢你
Thank you so much.
我已看了一半，不知道结局我会很气愤
I'm halfway through reading it.
坐吧，不如一起坐
Oh, here. Why don't you join me?
我叫桑雅
I'm Sonya.
我叫奥图
I'm Otto.
跟我父亲同名
It was my father's name.
我正要去探望爸爸
I'm on my way
我逢星期四都去
I go every Thursday.
你经常坐这班火车？
Do you take this train a lot?
不，我只是进城参加入伍体检
Oh, no, I had to come into town
天啊
Oh, God.
那一定很艰难
你不知道在那边会面临什么
- 你什么时候出发？
- 我不…
还有一段时间
Not for a while.
麻烦车票
Tickets, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
行了，谢谢
All right, thank you.
你好像上错车了，这是东行票
I'm afraid you're on the wrong train.
我一定是…
I must have, um...
我下一个站下车
I'll get off at the next station.
多少钱？
Uh, how much is it?
1.75 元
Uh, $1.75.
一元
One.
给你，我有些零钱
Here. I have some change.
谢谢
Thank you.
给你，祝你今天愉快
There you go. Thank you. Have a good day.
还剩 25 分
A quarter to spare.
是 1964 年的
It's 1964.
纯银的
-It's pure silver.
那你留着吧，代表幸运的
Keep it, then. It's lucky.
对，没错
Yes, it is.
（谢谢，这道菜很有趣）
嘿，奥图！
现在出来巡视太晚了，不是吗？
不是
No.
不是吗？你不是该已上班？
No? Aren't you supposed to be at work?
不是
No.
好极，你想过来吃午餐吗？
Oh. Cool.
午餐
-Lunch.
是啊
Yeah.
不，不行
No, no.
吃猪里脊，若你改变主意的话！
Well, it's pork tenderloin,
不，不行
No, no, no, no.
嘿，不好意思
Hey, excuse me.
就是你
It was you.
这是私家路，这闸是为了减少行车
This is a private road, and these gates
而不是让白痴司机绕过闸门、辗坏草地
Not so idiot drivers can go around them
好吧，被你抓到了
我是美利健四德的
我会叫管理员过来帮你修好，好吗？
I'm gonna have the groundskeeper
像新的一样，甚至更好
祝你今天愉快，好吗？
立规矩自有原因
The rules are here for a reason.
我知你们打算做什么
I know what you guys are up to.
好吧，安达臣先生，随你怎么说
Okay, Mr Anderson. Whatever you say.
继续巡视小区吧
Keep up the neighbourhood watch.
出来，你只衰猫！
-Get out here, you little bugger!
出来啊
Come on. Yeah.
出来！
Get out here!
你再丢一块石头
You throw one more rock,
我发誓我会一脚
踢你只老鼠狗上屋顶
我不是对你家丢石头
那只衰猫抓伤了王子
我要杀了那只畜生
I'm gonna kill that piece of shit.
不，不行
No, you're not.
你在乎什么？它是只野猫
What do you care? It's feral.
可能满身奇怪疾病
It's probably full of all sorts
你也很可能有，但我不会向你丢石头
So are you, most likely.
安迪
Andy.
- 怎么了？
- 你听到他这次说什么吗？
我跟你讲过他怎骂我
I told you before about
趁早走吧
Get outta here while you can.
我不是你的朋友
I'm not your friend.
地产公司的人说
会把这条街的老人都送去老人院
越快越好！
The sooner the better!
哈罗
-Hello.
- 又怎么了？
- 我只想还扳手给你
- 原来家具里有
- 恭喜
我还焗了些吃的给你
And I made you some salpores de arroz.
是浓酱鸡吗？
Is that chicken and mole?
不，是萨尔瓦多传统曲奇
我父亲最爱吃，所以…
很美味的，你会喜欢
They're delicious.
没错，因为是我焗的
Yes, because I made them.
还有，奥图
你有梯可以借给我吗？
我们的窗卡住了
Our window is jammed.
你为什么需要梯？
Why do you need a ladder?
因为是楼上的窗
Well, it's the one up there.
打不开
It won't open.
你想从外面打开？
And you're gonna try to open it
是，没错
Yeah. Right.
我去拿外套
I'll get my coat.
好，谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
我喜欢它这样挥手
I like how his hands are waving.
插上手臂
Let's put the arm in.
- 好极
- 安妮塔
奥图，抱歉打扰你
但我们没有暖气
你能来看看吗？
Could you come take a look?
试试帮散热器放气
Try bleeding your radiators.
我要怎样做到？
How would I go about that?
就是帮散热器放气
By bleeding the radiators.
奥图，别那么无礼
Otto. Don't be rude.
我没有无礼
I wasn't being rude.
有时听奥图的说话很难分辨
Well, it's hard to tell the difference
没错
Yeah.
顺便一说，我们刚搬到 206 号
By the way, we, uh, just moved to 206.
- 我叫玛莉素
- 我叫汤美
- 欢迎你们，亲爱的
- 幸会
我叫安妮塔
I'm Anita.
以前都是我老公鲁本处理暖气
My husband, Reuben,
但我们都知他迟早没法…
-Okay.
再处理家里的事
when he wouldn't be able to handle things
或许鲁本密谋夺权时
就该想到这一点
Oh...
那已是很久以前的事
That was a long time ago.
夺权？
A coup?
那是误会
It was a misunderstanding.
曾有人想夺权
It was a coup.
奥图，你就不能帮
安妮塔的散热器放热吗？
不行，因为散热器不能放热
No. Because you don't breathe radiators.
是要放气
You bleed them.
- 亲爱的，看这斜台
- 那是桑雅的
- 拖车用得着
- 放下它
放下它！谁说你可以碰的？
Put that down!
- 对不起，奥图
- 你们都滚！走！
拿梯子走
全部走，通通都走
- 好吧
- 谢谢
小心
Watch out.
知道了
-Right. Right.
- 谢谢！
-Thank you!
不，你在这里做什么？
No. What are you doing in here?
你怎么进来的？
How did you get in here? Come on.
快，走啊！出来！
Come on. Go! Get outta there.
不，出来！出来！
No, get out. Get out of there.
好了，快走
Come on, go.
嘿
-Hey.
放开！
Let go!
-Let go.
你敢抓伤我，我就咬你
You scratch me, I'll bite you.
受教训了吧
-That'll teach you.
蠢猫
Stupid cat.
- 嗨，奥图！
-Hi, Otto!
O-T-T-O
Hm.
奥图
Otto. Um...
去年八月我借了花园水管给你
I loaned you my garden hose last August.
你还给我，我就帮你的散热器放气
If you give it back to me,
进来
Come in.
你的那些新邻居
他们看来为人不错，不是吗？
很不错
Lovely.
是啊，你可能很快会有更多新邻居
Yeah, well, you may have
地产公司的人，他们一直跟我们说…
The realty people,
鲁本和我必须搬走
Reuben and I have to move out.
不，简直是放屁
No, that's a load of crap.
这间屋不是他们的，是你们的
They don't own this house. You do.
对，我也是这样说
Yeah, well, that's what I said.
他们最近游说我们的儿子基斯
They, uh, have been
Oh.
现在他说我没能力再照顾鲁本
Now he's saying that I can
说他需要住进特殊疗养院
that he needs to be
而我就该搬去老人院
And I should move into a retirement home.
基斯懂个屁？
他是个蠢蛋，一直都是
他们不能迫你做任何事
They can't make you do anything.
他知道我们在这吗？
Does he even know we're here?
他当然知道
Of course he does.
别让他骗了你
Don't let him fool you.
以前的他还在
He's still in there.
Um...
我去找你的水管
Let me go find your hose.
最近整个小区都乌烟瘴气
The whole neighbourhood
他们连业主会都不再有
They don't even have
没人留下来打理这小区
No one left to keep things running.
不像我们以前那样打理
Not like we did.
我先讲清楚
Now, just to be clear...
我仍没有原谅你
I still haven't forgiven you.
我只是没意识到你会恶化得那么快
I just didn't realise
现在…
Now...
他们正摧毁我们辛苦建立的一切
they're tearing apart
我还没走呢，他们就想把我们抹去
I haven't even left yet,
老实说，我不会留在这里看着一切发生
Well, I am not staying around
我要走了
I'm leaving.
- 永远离去
- 准备吃午餐了？
- 我煮了你喜欢的忌廉粟米
- 噢，谢谢
谢谢，奥图
抱歉这么久才还给你
留下来吃午餐吗？
Um, you wanna stay for lunch?
是啊，安妮塔煮了猪里脊
Yeah, Anita made a pork tenderloin.
不了，我有很多事要做
No, I have a lot of things I have to do.
鲁本，你做什么，亲爱的？
Reuben, what are you doing, hon?
- 放手
- 你在做什么？
- 鲁本
- 放…
- 你在做什么？
手！
...go.
老天
Oh, man.
试试从里面打开
Try opening it from the inside a little.
比我想像中高
It's higher than I thought.
我有点头晕，老婆
I'm a little bit dizzy, honey.
Mmm.
Mmm. Mmm.
♪ Sun through the shadows ♪
♪ Light through the door ♪
♪ Your voice like an echo ♪
♪ That I can't hear anymore ♪
♪ So I follow your steps ♪
♪ While the love that you left ♪
♪ Is burned in my heart ♪
♪ With dreams in my mind ♪
♪ Of the next time that I ♪
♪ Have you in my arms ♪
♪ 'Cause I will tell you ♪
♪ The whole truth ♪
♪ That there's no colour ♪
♪ In the world without you ♪
看来我俩都要坐下一班车了
Looks like we'll both have
奥图
Otto.
跟你父亲同名
It was your father's name.
你记得
You remembered.
你要回去军人中心？
Did you have to go back
不，我想把车票的钱还给你
No, I wanted to pay you back
你邀请我去吃晚饭，不是更好吗？
Wouldn't it be nicer
♪ The best gift of this life ♪
♪ Is to see you up close ♪
♪ And now and again... ♪
进去吧？
Shall we?
好，进去吧
Yeah, let's go in.
你…
You're...
迟了十五分钟
...fifteen minutes late.
是吗？
Am I?
♪ So I write it all down ♪
♪ All these moments I've found ♪
♪ Til I see you, my love ♪
那么，你对什么感兴趣？
So, what kinds of things interest you?
哪方面的兴趣？
Interest me like...?
你热衷做什么？
What are you passionate about?
机器、引掣
Machines. Engines.
我喜欢了解事物怎运作
I like knowing how things work.
每个零件怎样令汽车运行畅顺
What each part does
这比人们想的更复杂
It's more complicated than people realise.
化油器要把汽油和空气恰当混合
A carburettor has to mix gas and air
然后火嘴必须点燃该混合物
and then the spark plug
驱动活塞
which drives the piston
连杆和传动轴…
and the connecting rods
你从哪里学来这么多汽车知识？
Where did you learn so much about cars?
来自我父亲
From my father.
我们只会谈这些，他是个好爸爸
It's all we really talked about.
可靠
Dependable.
他过身了
He passed away.
两个月前
Two months ago.
很突然的
It was sudden.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那你妈妈呢？
And your mom?
不太记得她了
Don't remember her much.
只记得她过身时的感觉
Just how it felt when she was gone.
你为什么不点主菜？
Why didn't you get an entrée?
我在家吃过饭了
I ate at home.
为什么？
Why?
那你就可以随便点菜
So you could order whatever you wanted.
听着，我骗了你
Look, I lied to you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没入伍，我体检不合格
I'm not in the Army.
若合格了，至少现在
我有工作可依靠，但是…
我不合格
But I don't.
而我不知道我要做什么
And I don't know what I'm gonna do.
我该走了
I should go.
奥图！
Otto!
来了
I'm coming.
I'm coming!
怎样？你想要什么？
What? What do you want?
- 你在这里做什么？
- 你在做什么？
- 我在找你
- 那你找到了
请你载我去医院？求求你
Can you please take me
汤美从梯上摔下来
救护车刚接走他
你可以开你那进口焗炉般的车去
Well, you can drive yourself
我没车牌
I don't have a licence.
- 你几岁了？
- 三十岁
而你没有车牌？
And you don't have a driver's licence?
我有学车许可证
I have a driving's permit.
只是从没去办之后各种手续
I just never got to the other parts.
仲有哪几种手续？
How many other parts are there?
拜托！
Please!
专心！请你听我讲！
Focus! Please, listen!
汤美进了医院
我们说话期间他可能已经死了
所以你要开车送我去医院
还是叫我去坐巴士？
- 我会开车送你去医院
- 谢谢
这很难吗？
Was it so hard?
你去哪里？
Where are you going?
我去叫孩子们！
I'm going to get the children!
孩子们？
The children?
（杜克逊医院）
抬起我！抬起我！
Pick me up, pick me up!
四围砰砰砰…不！不！
Bam everywhere. No! No!
打！打！打！
Smack, smack, smack!
这些公仔
These dolls.
他们是超级英雄吗？
Are they some kind of superheroes?
他们是摔角手，是的
Um, Luchador are wrestlers. Yeah.
摔角手
Wrestlers.
- 我找到熊先生的书！
- 我见到
她想你讲故事
She wants you to read to her.
没错
Exactly.
《你在吗？熊宝宝？》
"Are You There, Baby Bear?
“你在吗，熊宝宝？”熊先生说
'Are you there, Baby Bear?'
“在哪里？我的熊宝宝”
'Where, oh where, is my Baby Bear.'"
不，要说得像熊一样
No, talk like a bear.
熊不会说话
Bears don't talk.
这一只会
Um, this one does.
“在哪里？我的熊宝宝？”
"'Where, oh where, is my Baby Bear?'
“熊宝宝，你在吗？在那棵树上？”
'Are you there, Baby Bear,
不，那是猫头鹰！
-No, it's an owl!
“这里没其他动物，只有宝宝和我”
"'There's nobody here but baby and me.'
“熊宝宝，你在吗？在地下深处？”
'Are you there, Baby Bear,
我不是熊宝宝
I'm no Baby Bear.
我是贝贝！
I'm Beppo!
- 嗨，贝贝！
-Hi, Beppo!
- 想看魔术吗？
- 想！
其实我正给她们讲故事
Actually, I was reading to them.
“其实我正给她们讲故事”
熊先生抱怨说
我可以借个硬币吗，熊先生？
Say, could I borrow a coin, Mr Bear?
可以，可以…求求你？
Yes, yes, yes, please?
求求你？
Please, please, please?
借啊！借啊！
-Yes, yes, yes!
要还给我
I need this back.
当然
Absolutely.
那套小丑装不是他的，是医院的
He doesn't even own the costume.
他要赔钱
He's gonna have to pay for that.
贝贝代表快乐
他来这里做义工的
奥图，你到底做了什么？
Otto. What the hell did you do?
没什么
Nothing.
奥图爷爷打了小丑
Abuelo Otto hit the clown.
- 我没有
- 有，你有
摔角手爷爷！
Abuelo Luchadoro!
摔角手！
Luchadoro!
都是那小丑的错
It was all the clown's fault.
Ooh!
它要去哪里？
Where is it going?
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
你来吧
Here you go.
吹口气
Blow.
哇！在这里！
Wow! Here it is!
- 你怎做到的？
- 是魔法啊
谢谢
-Thank you.
希望你们有神奇的一天！
I hope you have a magical day!
- 拜拜！
- 拜拜，贝贝！
- 谢谢
- 等等
这不是我的硬币
This isn't my quarter.
从你耳朵出来的，所以是你认错
Well, it came from your ear, sir,
不，这不是我的硬币
No, this isn't my quarter.
“不，这不是你的硬币”
"No, no, no. This is not your quarter."
听着，我给了你一个硬币
我说过要拿回来
- 你想要一元？
- 你换了这个给我
- 调包把戏
- 你给了我这硬币
奥图会有麻烦吗？
Is Otto going to get in trouble?
- 只是个硬币
- 不，不是
- 看到里面的铜吗？
- 他不是呼唤铜
- 我给你的是 1964 年的硬币
- 请冷静
还给我！在哪？
I want it back! Where is it?
- 在你身上的！
- 警察，帮我
129，有小丑纠纷
129. We have a clown situation.
在哪？
Where is it?
请放开小丑！先生！先生！
Let go of the clown! Sir! Sir!
哈！1964 年
A-ha! 1964.
我的玩具在哪？
Where's my toy?
在你的背包里
It's in your backpack.
哪一格？有太多格
What pocket? There's a million pockets.
怎么了？
What?
我父亲也曾那样笑
My father used to smile like that.
我没在笑
I'm not smiling.
正是这样
Exactly.
你不应该这样对小丑
You should never be mean to a clown.
- 星形扳手呢，他要来吗？
- 看！
- 嘿，各位！
- 妈，他在那！
麻烦开车过去，我们去接他
Pull the car up please, so we pick him up.
奥图！
Otto!
-Yay! Yay!
- 多谢你开车载我们
- 拜拜，摔角手爷爷
- 谢谢，奥图
- 好了，晚安
- 拜拜！
- 再次多谢，奥图
拜拜啦
Bye, then.
好了，女士们
All right, ladies.
走吧
Let's go.
看你只新脚！似机械脚
Look at your new leg!
奥图！
Otto!
天啊，它死了吗？
Oh, my God, is he dead?
不，它可能只是睡着
No, he's probably sleeping.
奥图，不，求求你
抱它出来，拜托
不，你为什么不去？
No, why can't you?
因为我怀孕了
我不能碰猫，可能会沾到弓虫
它自己走进去的，自然可自己出来
Well, he got himself in there.
Ay.
你怎么能这样？
Why are you like that?
我同猫唔夹
I'm not good with cats.
嘿，老友，怎么了？
Hey, man. What's going on?
占美！占美，我们有…
Jimmy. Jimmy. We have a...
噢，惨了！
Oh, no!
要帮你保暖，老友！
We gotta warm you up, buddy!
是啊…小心些
Oh, yeah. Oh, be careful.
真惨
Oh, no.
噢，我来抱你
-Oh, I've got you.
它很冰冷
He's so cold.
我们该去哪？
Where do we go?
不，不行，会有弓虫
去奥图度
好了，走吧
我救起你了
奥图，开门
Otto. Open the door.
噢，没事的，老友
Oh, it's all right, buddy.
- 没事的，小猫咪
- 真可怜
好了，没事了
Okay. You're okay.
- 弄得我全地板都是雪
- 噢，对不起
天啊，这里太冷了
Oh, my God, it's so freezing here.
好了，这件怎样？
Okay, how about this one? Please?
不，不行
别碰那外套，留在那里
- 好了，可否拿张毛毯来？
- 给猫用？
- 不要紧，我搞得掂
- 你在做什么？
体温有奇效，我够大只又够暖
Oh, body heat works wonders.
我去开焗炉
I'm gonna turn on the oven.
别把那只猫放进我焗炉
You are not putting that cat in my oven.
我只想让屋内暖和些
No, I'm just trying to get
你的枱面好低，哪里买来的？
Your counters are so low.
我自己造的
I built them.
给桑雅，我的太太
For Sonya. For my wife.
她也很矮吗？
Ah. Is she short too?
桑雅去世了
Sonya passed away.
但她厨艺了得，不是吗？
She was a great cook though,
我以前常来这里吃饭
I used to eat here all the time.
Oh.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你们现在可以走了吗？
Well, can you go now?
我有事要做
I have things to do.
那么…见到你真好，一如以往
Well, it was great seeing ya, as usual.
嘿，谁来照顾这家伙？
Oh, hey, who's gonna look after this guy?
你
You are.
-Aw.
好吧
Okay.
现在正经地问我
Now ask me the right way.
那真的很美
It was so beautiful too.
好了，我饿了
Okay, now I'm hungry. Now I'm hungry.
（恭喜 1978 年工程班）
我们看看
Let's see.
（工程学院）
“校委会特此证明奥图安达臣”
"The Board of Regents hereby certifies
“已完成工程系学士学位所有要求”
having completed all the requirements
你有没有想过…
Would you ever wanna...
想过结婚？
get married?
- 如果你有…
- 看着我
现在正经地问我
Now ask me the right way.
你愿意…
Will you...?
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
愿意！
Yes!
愿意
-Yes.
Yes.
愿意！愿意！
-Yes! Yes!
- 天啊！
- 帮手报警呀
他掉下去了！
He fell down!
- 找人帮他啊！
- 影他呀，不，拍片
有无搞错
Oh, for God's sake.
- 有无人帮手呀？
- 天啊，他摔倒了
- 抬他上来！救命！
- 嘿！你能动吗？
起来！快！你要起来！
You gotta move! Come on! You gotta get up!
来帮我好吗？
Will somebody help me?
- 快啊
- 影低！影啊！
- 拍片呀
- 拍到了，我见到他
拍近点
Zoom in on his face.
- 快说事件经过
- 我们本来要去博物馆…
看着我
Look at me.
打个招呼
Say hello.
吸一口气，奥图
Take a breath, Otto.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
快握住我的手！
Take my hand now!
你疯了吗？你会无命
Hey, are you out of your mind?
先生，你救了他一命
Sir, you saved his life.
他救了他一命
He saved that guy's life.
真了不起
You're amazing. Oh, my God.
- 总之追踪我们
- 追踪我们
Hey.
你想吓死我吗？
Are you trying to scare me to death?
你看这个
Look at this.
Um...
艾比想给新邻居画幅画
Abbie wanted to make a picture
她想送给你
She wants you to have that.
那是你
That's you.
她总是把你画成彩色
She always draws you in colour.
“总是 ”是什么意思？
What do you mean, "always"?
Hm!
我有个非常好的主意
I have a very good idea.
你可以教我开车
You can be my driver's instructor.
不
No.
不，不要
No, no, no.
我没时间教你
I don't have time for that.
但放心，我会付油钱和其他费用
But don't worry,
嘿，你们在这，我到处找你们
Hey, there you guys are.
嗨，占美，你在做什么？
-Hi, Jimmy. What are you doing?
- 猫在里面？
- 是
天啊！冷静点，老友
-Oh, jeez! Calm down, dude.
它真的不喜欢这纸箱
-He really doesn't like this.
让它出来啊
Let him out of the box.
好吧…对不起，老友
Okay. Sorry, buddy.
你打算做什么？带它去散步？
What do you think you were doing?
我必须把它带回来，我忘了我会过敏
Well, I had to bring him back.
所以…
-So...
- 噢，占美
- 是啊
我涂了点燕麦，但没帮助
I put oatmeal on it,
好了，跟我来吧
汤美去年的药还在
- 他找到了黄蜂巢
- 你确定？
- 我不想烦到你
- 不要紧，但别抓了
我觉得该抓一下
-Don't scratch.
嘿！那只猫怎么办？
Hey, hey, what about the cat?
看来它是你的了，奥图
Uh, looks like he's yours now, Otto.
要爱它
Love him.
进纸箱
-Get in the box.
Get in the box.
进纸箱
对不起，我还没来陪你
Sorry I haven't come yet.
那比我想像中难…
It's been harder than I thought to...
而且现在它搬进来了
And now he's moved in.
我有只猫
I have a cat.
我要想想如何安置它
I have to figure out what to do with him.
然后我就去找你
桑雅，我保证
我想念你
I miss you.
♪ And I finally see ♪
♪ How your love is the best of me ♪
♪ Yeah, there's so much
I want you to know ♪
♪ Guess I'll wait till you're home ♪
噢，不行
Oh, no, no, no.
你不能霸占我的床
You are not taking over my bed.
这才是你的床
This is your bed.
你宁愿睡在外面
Would you rather sleep outside,
回到雪地里？
back in the snow?
我大可以安排
That can be arranged.
你会是我们孩子最想要的好爸爸
You'll be the best dad
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
怎么了？
What?
你踩那单车就是来派传单？
Is this what you use that bike for?
是啊，是我的工作
Yeah. It's my job.
做侍应和入油才是工作
Waiting tables and pumping gas,
我还在薄饼店返夜班
周末返夜冷店，所以…
Oh.
你是安达臣先生，对吗？
-Huh.
Mm-hm.
你以前常来学校的演讲
You used to come
几时的事？
When was that?
安达臣太太是我的老师
Mrs Anderson was my teacher.
她是第一个不把我当怪胎的人
She was the first person
因为我是跨男
'cause I'm transgender.
她是第一个叫我新名字的人
She was the first
她叫其他老师也这样做
She got the other teachers to do it too.
那样在学校真的帮到我
It really helped me at school.
我不会再在这里派传单了
I won't leave these here anymore.
嘿
Hey.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
- 马康
-Malcolm.
奥图
Otto.
很高兴认识你，奥图
Nice to meet you, Otto.
嘿！
Hey!
奥图！好消息
Otto! Good news.
安迪在教我开车
Andy's teaching me how to drive.
学坏师
The wrong way.
- 谢谢你
- 不客气
- 好了
- 好吧
- 拜拜
-Bye.
泊车档！
Park!
你仍在用前进档！它是自动波
You're still in drive! It's an automatic.
你仍在用前进档
你要转到泊车档
什么？
In what?
拜拜！
Bye!
Mm.
- 救命！
- 我来了！
来救公主！
Saving the princess!
- 好了，来了！
- 奥图！
奥图来了！我妈焗了曲奇
Otto's here!
嘿，奥图，进来吧
Hey, Otto. Come in.
我无法忍受看着
一个蠢材教另一个蠢材开车
你！穿好外套，够钟上堂
You. Put on your coat. It's lesson time.
什么？
What?
你要教我？真的？
You're gonna teach me? Really?
奥图，谢谢你！
Otto, thank you!
谢谢
-Mm.
我很快出来！
I'll be right out!
你真的太好人了，奥图，谢谢
That's really, really nice of you, Otto.
Mm.
我教过一次
I tried once.
Mm.
你们要乖啊
You guys, okay.
拜拜，奥图！
Bye, Otto!
- 妈妈要去兜风了
- 小心点，老婆
- 拜拜，妈妈！
- 拜拜，我的宝贝
你们玩开心点！
-Have fun, guys!
拜拜，妈妈！
Bye, Mama!
好了
All right.
大人都不在了，来吧！
-No more grown-ups. Come on!
奥图，可以开我们的车吗？
Ah. Otto, pero can we go in our car?
因为我只开过自动波
Because I've only ever driven automatic.
不行
No.
我要正经教你开车，上车
I'm teaching you how to drive. Get in.
好了，快到红灯了
你要停下来
好，我要踩离合器，对吗？
Okay, but I get the clutch, right?
你要踩离合器，然后踩刹掣
You get the clutch
- 踩刹掣，还是离合器？
- 继续踩住离合器
踩刹掣，我踩离合器
Put in the brake, I put the clutch.
离合器和刹掣，然后踩刹掣
Clutch and brake. And now brake.
刹掣…刹掣
-Brake. Brake.
- 别大声骂我
- 我没大声骂你
踩离合器…踩了！踩了！
Clutch in. It's in, it's in!
我们要停下来，然后…
We're going to stop, and...
踩离合器，再踩刹掣
刹掣…刹掣…
那辆车停了，别撞上去！
刹掣，刹掣！
好了，放手吧
Yes. All right, let go.
天啊
Oh, my God.
刹掣
Brake.
踩离合器和刹掣
It's clutch and brake.
我开车很差
I suck at this.
- 我很差
- 你还在学
天啊，我差点撞上那辆车…就这么近
Oh, my God, I almost hit the car.
不要紧，那是混能车
It doesn't matter. It's a hybrid.
那是混能车，好吧
It's a hybrid, okay.
- 也许我该退后
- 不要…
- 你这样停就好
- 但我跟它很贴
- 不要紧
- 我不用倒后？
只需等绿灯
-Just wait for the green light.
好了，踩离合器
And here we go. So press in on the clutch.
慢慢踩油
And give it a little gas.
慢慢松开离合…
Slowly let out on the clu--
你还未入档
Oh, you're not in gear.
绿灯了！
Green!
踩离合器，转到第一…
你不用扭车匙
- 开车啦！
- 只需踩…
- 天啊
- 踩…
慢慢松开离合器
-Slowly let out the clutch,
- 然后踩油门
- 我做不到
- 你只需要那样做
不，奥图
奥图，不要
怎么了？
What?
老天
Oh, shit.
你有病吗？
What is wrong with you?
她在学开车
She's learning how to drive.
你以前不用学开车吗？
Did you not have to learn how to drive?
冷静，老爹，嘿！嘿！
Calm down, old man. Hey, hey.
我不是你老爹！你这混帐！
I'm not your old man! You son of a bitch!
如果你再响鞍
If you honk that horn one more time,
那将是你临死前做的最后一件事，听到吗？
it'll be the last thing you do.
明白吗？
¿Comprende?
惨了
Oh, shit.
现在你听我讲
Now you listen to me.
你生了两个孩子，很快就生第三个
You have given birth to two children.
你从非常遥远的国家来到这里
You have come here
你学会了一种新语言
You learned a new language,
你来接受了教育，嫁了个笨老公
you got yourself an education
你维系了全家人
and you are holding that family together.
你学开车完全不会有问题
You will have no problem
天啊，这世界充满了蠢材
My God,
他们都学得懂，何况你不是蠢到贴地
who have managed to figure it out,
好了…
So...
离合器
Clutch.
换档
Shift.
踩油
Gas.
开车
Drive.
Ah...
很不错
Yeah.
Que bueno.
很不错
好的，这里有位
Okay, there's a spot right there.
上前，平行泊车
Just pull up, parallel,
把车倒后
直到泵把与侧视镜一致
（斯登面包）
现在泊直
Now straighten out.
一直退到路边
Back up all the way up to the curb.
- 上少少
- 少少
然后停
And stop.
空档
Neutral.
刹掣
-Brake.
车匙
Key.
成功了？
Is that it?
成功了
That's it.
而且来得刚刚好
-And we're right on time.
我可以了
I have it.
-Uh-huh.
这些是豆蔻面包
-These are semlors.
瑞典的长条泡芙
-Swedish éclairs.
会吃得脏乱
They're a little messy.
但尝尝吧
-But let's try.
用手指按住
With your finger.
Mmm!
你怎找到这地方的？
How did you find this place?
这里是桑雅最喜欢的
This was Sonya's place.
我们以前逢星期六一点都来
We used to come here
然后呢？之后做什么？
And then? What?
两点钟回家
Go home at- 00.
我会洗车、打蜡
I'd wash and wax the car,
她会批改作业、煮饭
然后余下时间都看书
什么书？
What kind of books?
她喜欢的书
-Her books.
我试过看过几本，但…
I tried to read some of them, but...
我就是…
I'm just...
我不喜欢看书
I'm not into books.
她的朋友说，我俩像白天与黑夜
Her friends said
遇到桑雅前，我的人生是黑白的
My life was black-and-white
她就是那抹色彩
She was the colour.
我一定会喜欢她
I would have liked her.
她很有个性
She was a force of nature.
她说服到学校成立特别计划
She convinced the school
帮助有额外需要的孩子
for the kids that needed extra help.
很多孩子有家庭问题
A lot of kids had problems at home
或社交焦虑
or, uh, social anxieties.
但当桑雅教过他们之后
But by the time Sonya was done with 'em,
他们都开始会背莎士比亚了
they were reciting Shakespeare.
我碰到她的一位学生
I ran into one of her students,
就在前天
just the other day.
那孩子叫马康
A kid named Malcolm.
你要多些忌廉
You need more cream.
好吧
Okay.
我们刚搬进来时，和街坊相处得很好
We all got along fine, of course,
像天赐大礼
It was like a gift.
欢迎搬来这里
Welcome to the neighbourhood.
- 嗨，我叫桑雅
- 我叫安妮塔
桑雅和安妮塔是好朋友
Sonya and Anita were best friends.
所以我拿我的六角扳手…
So I got my Allen keys...
而鲁本和我也很相似
And Reuben and I were a lot alike.
慢点！
Hey! Slow down!
大部分观点都一样
About most things.
蠢材
Idiot.
但人是会变的
But people change.
或许他们都一成不变
Or they don't change.
有些事发生了，然后人们渐渐疏远
Things happen. People drift apart.
筑起了墙，冒犯了对方
They build walls. They take offence.
（福特）
谁知道为什么
Who knows why.
或许是那些建筑工程令大家发狂
Maybe it was all the construction
你知嘛，那座山上曾有片树林
You know, there used to be
所以这里才叫桦木庄
That's why they call it Birchwood.
他们开始建那些公寓
Then they started building
砍掉所有白桦树
and cut down all the birches.
他们根本不知道，直至我们告诉他们
They didn't even realise
鲁本和我
Reuben and I.
这是夺位之前发生？
But this was before the coup?
噢，没错，鲁本和我当时是朋友
Oh, yeah, yeah.
在那之后，我们什么事都有分歧
After that,
（福特）
（雪佛兰）
几年后，他们的儿子基斯
接受了一份在日本的工作
他从此再没回来探望他们
and I don't think
鲁本和他一直相处不来
-Oh.
总之，我就在那时决定和解
Anyway, that's when I decided
鲁本
Reuben.
嘿
Hey.
桑雅以前送我这瓶酒
Sonya gave me this a while back.
从没找到机会去喝
Never found the occasion.
我想我们或可重新做朋友
I thought maybe we could start fresh.
嘿，你想看我的新车吗？
Hey, would you like to see my new car?
好
Sure.
是新型号
It's a new model.
新出的
Just came out.
看啊
Voilà.
丰田？
A Toyota?
你买了架丰田
You bought a Toyota.
Celica GT 开篷车
Celica GT convertible.
五档自动波
Five-speed automatic.
你必须与时并进
You gotta change with the times.
奥图！
Otto!
我不知道鲁本发什么疯
但那时候我就知道失去了他
一个人必须坚持他所相信的事
I mean, a man has to stand up
即使那是一架福什么车
Even if it is an F-O-R-D.
你和桑雅有想过生孩子吗？
And you and Sonya,
好了，两点了
Well,- 00.
好吧
Okay.
Yes.
我想知你今晚可否帮个忙
I was wondering
我和汤美没太多机会出去约会
Me and Tommy don't get a lot of time
而孩子快要出世
before the baby comes.
我不会开车送你们去约会
I'm not gonna drive you two
不，我们会坐的士
No. We're gonna take a cab.
那你需要我做什么？
What do you need me for, then?
- 妈妈，我没有！我为何要那样做？
- 是你！
- 还给我！
- 你捉我啊！
好了，你两个，拜托
You guys, por favor.
学会分享你们的一切
And learn to share your everything.
我不确定做得来
I'm not sure about this.
不，别傻了，会很好玩的
No. Don't be silly.
但你要记住
艾比必须在九点前睡，好吗？
没问题？
-You're good?
好了，警报密码是 4491…4491
So, alarm code, 4491. 4491.
我会设为 “防盗留守”
你有留心吗？
若你想出去
So if you wanna go out,
只需按这个掣，它就会解除警报
you just have to press this button here,
我会留在屋里
I'll be right here.
对，没错
Right. Yeah.
但世事难料
Well, you never know.
- 要对奥图爷爷好一点，好吗？
- 我们会的！
里面没朱古力奶
I don't see chocolate milk in here.
要用糖浆做
但不要加太多，她会睡不着
给我牛奶
Give me milk.
那是什么？
What is that?
烂鬼垃圾洗碗机
That's the goddamn useless dishwasher.
爸爸说想把它丢出窗口
Dad said he wanted
但妈妈说不准爸爸再开窗
but Mom said Dad isn't allowed
头
Head.
Cabeza
Cabeza.
- Cabeza
很好
Good.
眼
Eyes.
Ojos
Ojos.
- Ojos
很好
Good.
手臂，Brazo
Arm. Brazo.
很好
Good.
我不认为这是个好主意
I don't think this is a good idea.
为什么？
Why?
因为没有人打得赢摔角手
Because no one stands a chance
摔角手爷爷！
Abuelo Luchadoro!
帮我，帮我
Help me, help me.
等等，是他先出手的
Wait, no, he started it.
- 准备好？
- 挞死你！
挞落去，打！打！空手道斩！
Rub it and smack! Smack! Karate chop!
（安第斯大学 玛莉素孟德斯）
（加州大学 玛莉素孟德斯）
Huh.
哇，静得离奇，对吧？
Wow, it's awfully quiet, huh?
嘿，各位
-Hey, guys.
嗨
Hi.
她睡着了
She was already asleep.
今晚顺利吗？
How was it?
- 很好
- 你今晚做得很好，奥图
拍拍背赞赞自己
You should pat yourself on the back.
- 谢谢，奥图
- 不客气
现在退出
Exit now.
晚安
Have a good night.
好了
Okay.
他怎做到的？
How did he do that?
- 嗨，奥图
- 马康
你换档时，听不到链条响吗？
You can't hear your chain rattle
- 我的单车很旧了
- 别怪单车
你只需调你的变速器
You just have to adjust your derailleur.
- 我的什么？
-你的变速器要调整
不好意思
Uh, excuse me.
- 嗨，我是莎莉肯兹
- 嗨
我是社交媒体记者
I'm a social media journalist.
我想找奥图安达臣
I'm, um, looking for Otto Anderson.
你确定真的要找他？
Are you sure you wanna do that?
哇，太好了，犀利
Wow. It's great. That's amazing.
你好好对它，它也会好好对你
You treat it right, it'll treat you right.
给你，全套留着吧
Here. Keep the set.
谢谢，奥图
Thanks, Otto.
不敢相信我竟然帮你
把垃圾丢到别人的草坪
两份工作还不够吗？
Isn't two jobs enough?
我在存钱买车
I'm saving up for a car.
- 是吗？
- 是啊
哪款车？
What kind?
大众
Volkswagen.
小姐，你挡住了车库
Young lady, you're blocking the garage.
安达臣先生？我叫莎莉肯兹
Mr Anderson? My name is Shari Kenzie.
我是社交媒体记者，我…
I'm a social media journalist, and I--
那是什么？
What is that?
我有个网上系列叫《平凡英雄》
I have an online series
你前几天在火车站做的事很了不起
What you did the other day
你救了那个人一命
You saved that man's life.
你找错人了
You have the wrong guy.
不，我没有
我看过那短片几十次
- 是你
- 短片？
你没看过？
You haven't seen it?
有乘客用手机影低，放了上网
Oh. A commuter recorded what happened
评论中有人认出你，所以我才追踪到你
Someone in the comments recognised you.
已超过一百万观看次数
It's gotten over a million views.
一百万？一百万
A million? A million.
为什么人们总爱多管闲事？
Why can't people mind their own business?
因为像你这样的故事令人鼓舞
Because stories like yours are inspiring.
若我可和你谈几分钟…
If I could just talk to you
不行，我现在有太多事要做
No, now I've got too many things
被你救起的人
我帮他录了一段片
你该看看
You should see this.
- 奥图！嗨！
- 我找找看
早晨
Good morning.
Uh...
准备好再教我开车了？
-So you ready for another driving lesson?
- 现在不方便
- 不方便？
哈罗？嘿，我还在里面！
Hello? Hello? Hey, I'm still in here!
- 我没锁门
- 哈罗？
扭门柄，开门
Turn the knob, open the door.
你以前开过门吧？
-Opened a door before, haven't you?
蠢材
Idiot.
奥图！是我
Otto! It's me.
她走了
She's gone.
好极，我今早未巡视完
Good. I'm not through with my rounds.
“社交媒体记者”？
"Social media journalist"?
那到底是什么鬼？
What the hell does that even mean?
一群蠢蛋用相机对着自己
Buncha knotheads pointin'
我认为你处理得很好
I thought you handled it really well.
我指把她关在车库里
I mean, closing her in your garage.
简直是…绝世好计
That was, like, excellent strategy.
做得好
-Good job.
奥图，还有我在想
你为我们做了那么多
- 我也想为你做点事
- 我不需要任何东西
我觉得你有时该好好吃一顿，不是吗？
Well, I think you could do
那些曲奇…
Those cookies...
那些什么？传统曲奇？
The what? The "salporanz"?
那些不太差，不太差
Those are not bad. They're not bad.
还有，我在想
And, also, I was thinking
我可帮你清理房子、清理前廊
that I can help you clean out your house
帮你收起桑雅的外套和鞋子
and help you pack the coats and shoes
不需要
That's not needed.
是没必要，但那可帮你放下
No, but it can help you move on.
我不想放下
I don't wanna move on.
她会永远在你心里
She's always gonna be with you.
但你还在这里
-But you're still here.
够了
That's enough.
当我爸去世后
我妈她停止了生活
- 她不再像以前那样…
- 别再说了！
- 闭嘴
- 好！别呼喝我
为何别人总爱管闲事？蠢材
Why can't people mind
总是碍着我
Interrupting me at every turn.
越是口水多多
越覆盖了我对她声音的回忆
我不想把桑雅清出我的生活
I don't want to clear Sonya from my life.
她就是一切
She was everything.
遇到她之前，我人生一片空白
她过身后也是！
我也有某种意义
I'm something.
那混蛋！
That son of a bitch!
不，不行！
Uh-uh. No, no, no.
Uh-uh-uh. Uh-uh-uh.
停车！你停车！
Stop right there. You stop that car!
是你没关闸？你没关闸，对吧？
Did you leave that gate open?
只有你在乎
You're the only one who gives a damn.
我在乎人们是否守规矩
I give a damn
是，我知道
我知道你的一切
公司有份你的档案，这么厚
There's a file on you at the office.
我知道你太太的事
I know about your wife.
你把她的遭遇怪罪所有人
How you blame whatever happened to her
你收声
You shut up.
你别再多说一个字
Don't you say one more word.
冷静，奥图
听着，我不是要惹怒你
但你真的不应该独居
but you really shouldn't be living alone.
我意思是，我们了解你
多过你了解自己，所以…
你好好保重自己的心脏，好吗？
Just look after that heart of yours, okay?
你知道我的心脏怎么了？
What do you know about my heart?
嘿，你知道我的心脏怎么了？
Hey, what do you know about my heart?!
你这八卦混蛋！
You prying bastard!
奥图…奥图
Otto, Otto.
奥图，怎么了？
你还好吗？感觉还好吗？
若你想帮我，就去关闸
You wanna help me, close the gate.
奥图…奥图
Otto. Otto.
奥图
-Otto.
Otto.
应应我，奥图
求求你
奥图
Otto.
应应我，奥图
Talk to me, Otto.
奥图
Otto.
谢谢
Thank you.
（尼亚加拉大瀑布）
你戴得很好看
It'll be cute on you.
- 不
- 来嘛
宝贝，你戴得很好看
Honey, you look really cute.
（雾中少女号）
手给我
Give me your hand.
宝宝在踢我
The baby's really kicking.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ A-ha, ooh ♪
♪ I know you have a little life
In you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
♪ I know you have a little life
In you yet ♪
桑雅！
Sonya!
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
桑雅！
Sonya!
♪ I should be crying
But I just can't let it show ♪
♪ I should be hoping
But I can't stop thinking ♪
♪ Of all the things I should've said
That I never said ♪
♪ All the things we should've done ♪
桑雅！
Sonya!
♪ That we never did ♪
♪ All the things I should've given
But I didn't ♪
♪ Oh, darling ♪
♪ Make it go ♪
♪ Make it go away ♪
♪ Give me your hand ♪
♪ I know you have a little life
In you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
♪ I know you have a little life
In you yet ♪
♪ I know you have a lot of strength left ♪
♪ I should be crying
But I just can't let it show ♪
♪ I should be hoping
But I can't stop thinking ♪
嗨
Hi.
♪ Oh ♪
你醒了
There you are.
♪ Of all the things we should've said
That we never said ♪
♪ All the things we should've done
That we never did ♪
♪ Oh, darling, make it go away ♪
♪ Just make it go away now ♪
已经够了，亲爱的
That's enough now, darling.
你很生气，我知道
You're angry. I know.
还很难过
And sad.
我也是
So am I.
但我们还要过生活
But now we have to live.
又怎样了？
What now?
马康
Malcolm.
对不起，我不是故意要…
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to--
我不会开枪射你
I'm not gonna shoot you.
刚才是什么声音？
What was that noise?
发电机烧了，停电了
The generator blew and the power is out.
你想怎样？外面很冷
What d'ya want? It's freezing.
我希望你能让我在梳化睡一晚
I was hoping you might let me crash
这里不是酒店
This is not a hotel.
对，我很抱歉
No. I'm sorry.
你为什么不能回家？
Why can't you go home?
我爸赶我走
My dad kicked me out.
你可以睡梳化
There's a sofa you can use.
不要进饭厅，天花板要修理
Don't go into the dining room.
梳化在楼上，桑雅的旧书房里
It's upstairs in Sonya's old study.
他为何赶你走？
So why did he kick you out?
因为你现在是马康？
Because you're Malcolm now?
是，因为我是马康
Yeah, because I'm Malcolm.
因为我这样打扮
Because I dress like this.
我看太多书、不喜欢运动
随你挑个藉口
他觉得羞家，因为我是跨男
He's embarrassed 'cause I'm trans.
那他就是个蠢材
Then he's an idiot.
你睡这里
This is you.
尽量不要碰任何东西
Try not to touch anything.
好
Okay.
好吧
Well...
早晨，仍然无电
Good morning. The power's still out
最后几只蛋要尽快吃，趁未坏
so I cooked up the last of the eggs
希望你别介意
Hope you don't mind.
我要去巡视了
I have to do my rounds.
你不至少喝点咖啡？
Don't you at least want some coffee first?
好
Yes.
给你
There you go.
要蛋吗？
Uh, some eggs?
也好
I wouldn't say no.
好吧
All right.
那个罐
That can...
放这里
goes in here.
挂起它
Hang that up.
嘿，奥图！在巡视吗？
Hey, Otto! Making your rounds.
我可以跟你走吗？
我要走够步数
好吧
-Okay.
- 我叫占美
- 马康
- 幸会
- 谢谢
有证
Yes.
奥图，你可以走慢点
我心跳升了
有证
Yes.
奥图，你有听说
他们今午要送鲁本去疗养院吗？
谁？
Who is?
地产那班人
The Dye & Merika guys.
天啊
-My God.
他们说服了安妮塔卖屋
They convinced Anita to sell the house.
不，他们是与基斯做交易
No, they made the deal with Chris.
- 基斯？他不能那样做
- 他可以
当他们查到安妮塔患柏金逊症
After Dye & Merika found out
他们便找到了基斯，然后…
they tracked Chris down and--
- 柏金逊症？
- 是啊
所以去年基斯说服安妮塔签授权书
So last year Chris convinced Anita
以防她病情恶化
in case she got worse.
所以地产公司跟基斯做交易买屋
So Dye & Merika made the deal
那些混帐
Those pricks.
等等，安妮塔去年就知
自己有柏金逊症？
不，不可能的
No, that's not right.
她会告诉桑雅，然后桑雅会告诉我
She would've told Sonya.
嗯…安妮塔和鲁本
不想让你和桑雅知道
他们说你们已经够多麻烦事
They said you had enough
他们那样说？
They said that?
我要看你从地产公司收到的所有东西
I need to see everything
通知、信件
你有授权书副本吗？
你怎知道的？
How do you know about that?
- 你有吗？
- 有
- 去拿
- 好
还有鲁本和你病情的任何纪录
And any records
占美告诉你的？
Did Jimmy tell you that?
现在能拿来吗？
Can you get it now?
好
Yes.
我一直是个蠢材
I've been an idiot.
我沉浸于自己的烦恼，没再顾及其他人
I got so wrapped up in my own troubles,
于是以为别人也不顾及我
And I figured
朋友之间不应该这样
Friends shouldn't do that.
所以…
So...
隔了那么久，这句话很难开口
This isn't easy to say
但我很抱歉
But I'm sorry.
而且我会解决这一切
And I will sort all this out.
我要用你的电话
I need to use your phone.
为何不用你自己的？
Why can't you use your own?
我的停用了
Mine is disconnected at the moment.
- 为什么？
- 那不重要
我只需要用你的电话，好吗？
I just need to use your phone, okay?
你知道吗？
You know what?
不行
No.
- 不行？
- 不行
你不肯告诉我
为何你的电话停用了？
为何你要用我的电话？
你不肯告诉我
昨天你在街上发生什么事？
然后你返入屋，门都不肯开？
And then you went inside
你吓死我了，奥图
You scared me, Otto.
你知道我在外面等了多久吗？
Do you know how long I was out there?
我不知你是否出了事了
And I didn't know
也不知你会否出事
Or if something was gonna happen to you.
若我不该提起桑雅的外套，我道歉
And I'm sorry if I said
但我只是想帮忙
But I was just trying to help.
而你却把我关在外面
And you left me out there.
所以不行
你不能用我的电话
你认为你的生活很麻烦
因为人人都是蠢材
一切都要你一力处理，是吗？
and you have to do everything
是吗？
Right?
但你猜怎样？
But guess what.
只靠自己不行的
You can't.
没有人可以
No one can.
而你该感到高兴
And I think you should just be happy
因为有人肯帮你度过糟糕的一天
that someone was trying
即使他们是蠢材
Even if they're an idiot.
- 所以…
- 那班地产混蛋
要把安妮塔和鲁本赶走
are trying to force
所以我要用你的电话
That's why I need to use your phone.
好，好吧，进来
Okay, fine. Come on.
我们以前从没去过旅行
We had never had a vacation.
桑雅那时候已怀孕六个月
Sonya was six months pregnant.
她想在孩子出生前做些特别的事
And she wanted to do something special
所以我们去尼亚加拉大瀑布旅行
So we booked a trip to Niagara Falls.
回程时，巴士翻车了
On the way back, the bus crashed.
车厂说过刹车有问题要回收
There'd been a recall on the brake lines,
但那公司从没送修
but the company never had them fixed.
桑雅瘫痪了…
Sonya was paralyzed...
我们失去了儿子
and we lost our son.
三个月后，她终于可以回家了
After three months,
但他们已开始建造新公寓
But they had started building
社区中心和行人路
and the community centre
没一样是为轮椅人士设计
none of which were designed
建造商本可改变计划
The builders could have
但当时没有相关法律
而且他们也不在乎
我在乎
I did.
我在意
-We're putting in a new playground...
- 有其他地方给你妻子那样的人
- 我当时非常生气
什么意思？
她那样的人？那什么意思？
- 你想说什么？
- 放开我！
就在那时
他们投票罢免我做业主会主席
我想把他们全都赶走
I wanted to obliterate them all.
那些建筑商、地产商
还有巴士公司、巴士司机
我本来绝不罢休
I never would have let it go...
但桑雅不想这样
but for Sonya.
桑雅说我们要继续生活
Sonya said we had to keep living.
于是我便那样做
That's what I did.
我为桑雅而活
I lived for Sonya.
六个月前，她去世了
Six months ago she passed away.
癌症
Cancer.
我本打算随她一起去
I was going to join her.
所以我停用了电话
That's why I had them disconnect my phone.
但现在我认为
她希望我继续活下去
而且我还有很多事要做
And I have things to do.
（莎莉肯兹）
你在浪费时间，奥图
You're wasting your time, Otto.
交易已落实，鲁本要跟我们走
It's a done deal. Reuben's coming with us.
若你阻拦我们
And if you get in our way,
我会报警拉你
I'll have you arrested.
- 我什么也没做
- 你别想再踏前
你不能带走我老公
You are not taking my husband
安妮塔，拜托
我们这样做是为你好
你们是想夺取我的财产
What you're doing
我想鲁本在这里度过余生
I want Reuben to stay right here
（美利健四德疗养部）
和我一起在我们的家里
with me in our home.
好吧，但当你没能力时
谁来照顾鲁本？
谁来照顾你？奥图吗？
Who's gonna take care of you? Otto?
奥图的健康也不是很好
是吗，奥图？
我会照顾好他
I'll take care of 'em.
- 你在做什么？放低手机
- 安妮塔和鲁本就像我的家人
只要他们有需要，我会一直照顾
I'll take care of them
他们不是你的家人
They're not your family.
他们的儿子基斯已决定
他们不适合独自生活
所以我们现在要…
and so what we're doing is--
不好意思
基斯最后一次见父母是几时？
他住在日本，他们已疏远了十年
He lives in Japan.
基斯不会知道他父母的近况
Chris would have no idea
除非你告诉他
except for what you told him.
你是谁？
Okay. And who are you?
我叫莎莉肯兹
My name is Shari Kenzie.
社交媒体记者
Social media journalist.
我们正在现场直播
-We're streaming live right now.
好了，好了…
关上镜头，你不能拍
这是公共行人路
It's a public sidewalk.
你告诉安妮塔的儿子基斯
说她有柏金逊症
但安妮塔…
从未对任何人说过她有病
所以你怎知道的？
So how did you know?
我要查一下纪录
I'd have to check the records.
那边的安达臣先生是本地英雄
Mr Anderson over there
他告诉我，你也知道他的私人健康纪录细节
He tells me you know details
所以你和公司是如何…
So how are you and your company
非法取得长者的医疗纪录？
getting illegal access
好了，走吧，我们讲完了，讲完
Okay, let's go. We're done. We're done.
很高兴认识你们
Very nice to meet you.
不，你们玩完了！玩完了！
No, you're done. You're done!
- 该死的别再拍我
- 再见
- 我们成功了！
- 成功了！
拜拜，谢谢！
Bye, thank you!
我在一小时前上传了
安妮塔和基斯的故事
已有几十人回应说
Already dozens of people are saying
美利健四德强迫他们离开家园
Dye & Merika forced them
- 真容易
- 好了，拜拜
如果你有故事
请到我的频道和我分享
我拍到了，我拍到
-I got it. I got it.
嘿，你忘了关闸！
Hey, you forgot to shut the gate!
看到吗？他立即就投降，他放弃了
You see that?
在我们的年代
那些混蛋至少会抗争一下
他们还没能赶走我们
They haven't gotten rid of us yet.
是啊
Yeah.
真痛快，不是吗？
It does feel pretty good. Doesn't it?
友善的邻居，是否以前才会有？
Neighbourly neighbours,
我在这里与目击者
安妮塔占美一起了解情况
占美，你提到安妮塔和鲁本
就像你的家人
那到底是什么意思？
What does that mean, exactly?
我几乎每晚都在他们家吃饭
Well, I have dinner at their house
我知道你在等什么
你准备好吃午餐了，对吗？
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want.
哇，好了
Whoa. Here we go.
你们最近搬来这小区，感觉如何？
You moved into this community recently.
这里很美
-How has that been for you?
而你的家人，这里有人可…
And your family,
是啊
Yeah.
- 奥图？
- 这条片会在墨西哥播吗？
奥图！
Otto!
叫救护车！
Call an ambulance!
- 孟德斯女士？你可以见他了
- 好，好的
嗨，奥图爷爷
Hola, Abuelo Otto.
孟德斯女士？
Ms Mendes?
我是艾莉斯医生
I'm Dr Ellis.
安达臣先生把你列为近亲
Mr Anderson listed you as next of kin.
是，是的，没错
Yes. Yes, that's correct.
你叔叔差点丧命
他有跟你说过他的情况吗？
Mm...
不，不算有，没有
No, not really. No.
那叫肥厚型心肌病
It's called hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
基本上说，他的心太大了
Basically, his heart is too big.
太大？
Too big?
Mm-hm.
噢，好吧
Oh, okay.
Oh.
对不起，我没事
No, sorry. It's okay.
你真的同死神唔夹，你知道嘛
You're really bad at dying, you know that?
Ay.
奥图，我好像要生了
Otto, I think it's time.
好像要生了
I think it's time.
要生了
It's time.
我是心脏科医生，我帮你叫产科
Oh, uh, I'm a cardiologist.
快想办法，因为…要生了！
Do something. It's time!
（男孩！）
好了，准备？
All right, ready?
好了，各位影相！
All right, picture, everybody!
影相！影相！
Picture, picture, picture.
好了，准备好？
各位说“马可”
一、二、三
One, two, three.
马可！
Marco!
奥图！
Otto!
嘿，奥图，进来
-Hola. Hi!
各位，这是我们的朋友奥图
Everyone, this is our friend Otto.
嗨，奥图！
Hi, Otto!
嘿，奥图
Hey, Otto.
对不起，是关于前门那些车吗？
Sorry, is this about the cars
不是，我带了东西给你
No, I brought you something.
奥图
Otto.
我重新上了漆
I gave it a fresh coat of paint.
我很喜欢
I love it.
给宝宝的
-It's for the baby.
谢谢
好，帮我抱一会
- 为什么？
- 要叫汤美来看
抱着他…噢，他要哭了
Hold him. Oh, he's gonna cry.
-Whoa...
我很快回来，宝宝…好了
I'll be right back, bebé. Okay.
汤美斯？
Tomaso?
哈罗…乖
Hello. There we are.
我要给他奶嘴吗？
-Uh, should I put this thing back in him?
好了
There.
Oh. Yeah.
乖
Okay.
我是奥图爷爷
Yo soy Abuelo Otto.
知道吗？
Okay?
我给你示范怎样用
Uh, well, let me show you how this works.
你不需要做任何事
You don't have to do anything.
慢慢
Easy.
你的小脑袋…
Your little head...
好了，我们只需…
Now, you just go...
这样
like so.
Huh?
（桑雅）
桑雅，这是艾比和露娜
Sonya, this is Abbie and Luna.
她们有东西送你
They have something for you.
- 嗨，桑雅
-Hi, Sonya.
那是刚出世的小马可
-That's, uh, brand-new little Marco there.
还有玛莉素、汤美
我跟你说过他们的事
说“你好，桑雅”
Say, "Hola. Hola, Sonya."
她喜欢粉红色的花
She loved pink flowers, girls.
你们选得真好
You chose well.
我也喜欢粉红色
I like pink too.
你看到吗？
You see that?
- 准备好了？
- 是的
好了
Okay.
不
No.
不，不行
No, no, no.
搞什么，奥图
Come on, Otto.
（给玛莉素）
好了，马康
检查汽油
我们看看，怎么样？
And let's see, what does it say?
看来不错，对吗？
Looks good, right?
- 若你认为的话
- 好了
行了，好了
That's it. Okay, now...
这是你的手册
Here's your manual.
你的文件
Here's your papers.
还有车匙
And the key.
这是你的车了
It's your car.
你讲笑吧？
Are you kidding me?
不是
Nope.
什么？
What?
奥图！
Otto!
多谢…多谢你
Thank you. Oh, thank you.
- 天啊
- 免得你被大众糟蹋
我有车了！我有车了！
I have a car! I have a car!
- 这是你的车了！
- 讲笑吧？
奥图？你买了卡车！
Otto? You got your truck!
天啊！
Oh, my God!
想去兜风吗？
Wanna go for a ride?
- 去兜风？
- 卡车好型，奥图
小心
Be careful.
我喜欢你的车，奥图
I like your car, Otto.
是吗？你兜完风先知它的厉害
Yeah? Wait till you see how it rides.
好大啊
It's enormous.
这像是奥图的摔角手怪兽卡车
This is like Otto's luchador
你有漫画吗？
Yeah. Do you have any comics?
去吃瑞典长条泡芙？
Can we get Swedish éclairs?
这才是生活
This is livin'.
♪ Every morning I get up ♪
♪ Look out my window
I get up ♪
噢…好吧
Oh, okay.
♪ See the sunshine beating down ♪
♪ Every morning comes around ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Every morning... ♪
好了，谁准备好吃早餐？
Okay, who's ready for breakfast?
好了，吃吧
Okay. Here we go.
好吗？
Okay?
- 难以相信马可已经三岁了
- 你大个仔了
我去，老婆
-I'll get it, honey.
嘿，老婆？
Hey, honey?
Eh?
奥图没铲雪
Otto hasn't shovelled his walk.
看着你弟弟
Watch your brother.
去拿锁匙
Get the keys.
奥图？
Otto?
奥图
Otto.
是
Yeah.
玛莉素
Marisol.
Marisol,
若你在看这封信，不要担心
if you're reading this, don't worry.
我没做任何傻事
I haven't done anything stupid.
原来拥有宽大的心
It turns out having a big heart
并没听起来那么好
isn't as nice as it sounds.
医生警告过我，说这个病会让我丧命
The doctors warned me
所以我提前写好信，就是这样
so I planned ahead, that's all.
那只猫每天吃两次吞拿鱼
The cat eats tuna twice a day
而且如厕时不喜欢被人看着
and likes to do his business in private.
请尊重这一点
Please respect that.
我想举行葬礼
I would like a funeral.
我们在这天悼念你
We remember before you this day...
但别太夸张
But nothing overblown.
我们的弟兄奥图
...our brother Otto.
就是大家怀念一下
Just a remembrance of some sort...
与那些认为我有做好本份的人一起
for those people
一位本地英雄
亦是本节目的好友今天举殡
奥图安达臣
Otto Anderson.
占美，说几句关于奥图的话？
Jimmy, would you like to say
好，奥图，我们爱你
Yeah. Otto, we love you.
为向你致敬，马康和我
In your honour, Malcolm and I are doing
会接替你去巡视，不遗余力
逢工作日午餐时间去
你仍很重要
You loom large.
（爷爷安息）
我的律师会让你存取我的银行帐户
My lawyer will give you access
我从不浪费钱买垃圾
I never wasted money on crap,
所以你会有足够的钱供孩子们读书
so you'll have enough
你怎么做到的？
How'd you do that?
（桑雅安达臣青少年危机基金）
And do what you like with the rest.
余下的随你处置
乖仔
Oh, good boy.
那是狗狗蛋糕？
Is that a doggie cake?
我的小宝宝
My little monkey-poo.
敬奥图
To Otto.
这间屋及里面的一切，都是你的
The house, and everything in it, is yours,
只要你保证不会卖给那些地产混蛋
so long as you promise never to sell it
还有老天，玛莉素
And for God's sakes, Marisol...
汤美
Tommy.
不要让汤美开那架雪佛兰
...don't let Tommy drive the Chevy.
来吧
Come on.
其他人都不能开
Or anyone else, for that matter.
那辆车我只信得过让你开
I'm trusting it with you alone.
因为你不是蠢材
Because you are not an idiot.
奥图爷爷
Abuelo Otto.
♪ Sun through the shadows ♪
♪ Light through the door ♪
♪ Voice like an echo ♪
♪ I can't hear anymore ♪
♪ So I follow your steps ♪
♪ While the love that you left ♪
♪ Is burned in my heart ♪
♪ With dreams in my mind ♪
♪ Of the next time that I ♪
♪ Have you in my arms ♪
♪ 'Cause I will tell you the whole truth ♪
♪ That there's no colour ♪
♪ In the world without you ♪
（若你或任何人感到绝望
或有情绪危机，请向团体求助）
♪ How your love is the best of me ♪
（浏览 www.findahelpline.com
以寻救恊肋）
（为自己采取行动，并为他人提供帮助）
♪ Guess I'll wait till you're home ♪
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm ♪
♪ The way that you smile ♪
♪ When you think you're alone ♪
♪ The best gift of this life ♪
♪ Is to see you up close ♪
♪ Now and again ♪
♪ In the palm of my hand ♪
♪ I feel your touch ♪
♪ So I write it all down ♪
♪ In these moments I've found ♪
♪ 'Til I see you, my love ♪
♪ And I will tell you the whole truth ♪
♪ That there's no colour ♪
♪ In the world without you ♪
♪ And I finally see ♪
♪ How your love is the best of me ♪
♪ Yeah, there's so much
I want you to know ♪
♪ Guess I'll wait 'til you're home ♪
♪ Mm-mm-mm-mm. ♪
（字幕翻译：利慧中）
字幕翻译：
利慧中